Dr. Khalifa: [2:89] ...They rejected it. God's condemnation thus afflicts the disbelievers.
This is something that we talked about at
noon today, the ego.
As you see at the beginning of this book,
if you open the cover and go a few sheets,
you see that once God alone is mentioned.
Across from that, you see verses from the Old
Testament and the New Testament prophesying
the advent of the Prophet Muhammad, the final
prophet.
You see Moses in Deuteronomy 18:15 says "a
prophet like me," meaning a message-bearing messenger.
"...will the Lord, your God, raise up for you from
among your kinsmen;"
The Arabs and Jews are kinsmen.
"to him you shall listen."
And in Deuteronomy 18:19, God says "I will
raise up for them a prophet like you..."
God was speaking to Moses. "...from among their kinsmen and will
put my words into his mouth.
He shall tell them all that I command him.
If any man will not listen to My words which
he speaks in My name, I Myself will make him answer for it."
So, there's the prediction of the coming of
the Prophet Muhammad to the Jews.
Of course, the Jews also were expecting the
Messiah, Jesus, but when he came they wouldn't acknowledge him.
He was a human being like them. In spite of
the miracles that he showed them, they failed to recognize him.
They called him "imposter, a carpenter,"
not God's messenger.
It's just, you've seen today how bad the human
being is.
And we are the hardcore, egotistic gang among
God's creatures.
And as you see here, God is saying "I will
put My words in his mouth, to him you shall listen."
The Jews were aware of this, as far as the
Messiah was concerned, as far as Muhammad was concerned.
But it takes killing the ego to sit down and
listen to a human being like you and me.
This is what we're exercising now. We're
killing our ego in order to be redeemed, knowing
that we are listening to God's words in the
Quran.
We're submitting to God, in whatever God
does or says.
In the New Testament, you see the statement
here from John 14, 16, 17. "I will ask the
Father and He will give you another Paraclete,
to be with you always, the spirit of truth.
And in John 16:13, "when the spirit of truth
comes to you, he will guide you to all truth
and will announce to you the things to come."
So, the Christians also were given prophecy
about the Prophet Muhammad.
But when he came, brought the Quran, a
fantastic miracle, and he told them to worship God alone.
He told them who Jesus was, but they still
they cannot recognize him.
And this is extended to the Messenger of the
Covenant.
The Muslims are recipients of the scripture. And God told them in the scripture "the Messenger of the Covenant will come
after all the prophets
have delivered their messages."
And I'm quoting here Malachi. "Lo, I am sending My messenger to
prepare the way before Me, and suddenly,
He will come to the temple the Lord whom you
seek, and the Messenger of the Covenant whom you desire.
Yes, he is coming, says the Lord of hosts,"
which is Rabbil ‘Alameen in Arabic,
"but who will endure the day of his coming?
And who can stand when he appears?
For he is like the refiner's fire. He will
sit purifying and refining."
So again, it's the ego here. "Who will endure
the day of his coming?"
And how can you tell us that two verses that
the Quran we've known all along had two verses wrong in it?
How do you tell us that the Salat Prayer we've
been doing has been wrong?
And as you know, God blessed us, but because
we did this gradually. We fixed. We were doing everything wrong.
You and I were doing everything wrong.
And it takes killing the ego to give up things
that we've been taught by our parents and things
that we've been doing for a long time.
It takes, actually, it takes more courage and
more strength to say "I was wrong, I'm gonna do the right thing now."
"I'm gonna give up what was wrong even though
my parents taught me that."
But this is not the case with the majority
of people.
And this is what the Muslims are doing today.
I mean, the Quran clearly says "Muhammad was not the
last messenger. He wasn't the Messenger of the Covenant."
And I'm not harping on this issue, but just
the verse happens to state that, 89.
[2:89]  When a scripture came to them from God confirming what they have, and even though they used to prophesy its advent to the disbelievers, when their own prophecy came to pass, they rejected it. God's condemnation thus afflicts the disbelievers.
So, this brings out their disbelief, because
they claim to be believers.
And they claim to believe the Quran. Yet, when the Quran comes
to pass, a Quranic prophecy, they fail to uphold it.
These same people who are rejecting the Messenger of the Covenant would have rejected the Prophet Muhammad if they existed at the same time.
They would have been the first to fight him.
In fact, the Prophet struggled for 13 years
in Mecca.
They were rejecting him, stoning him, banishing
him, boycotting him and his followers.
These are the same people.
And those bigwigs who are meeting in Chicago
to preserve the finality of prophethood,
they would have been the first people to fight
the Prophet Muhammad if they existed in his time.
In fact, they are Abu Lahab's, every single
one of them.
I mean, who was Abu Lahab?
Abu Lahab was the religious leader of his time, following the corrupted religion of Abraham, Islam or submission.
And he opposed the Prophet Muhammad who was
telling him "worship God alone.
Here's the scripture of this religion."
And Abu Lahab faltered.
Number 90,
[2:90]  Miserable indeed is what they sold their souls for, disbelieving in God's revelations out of sheer resentment that God should bestow His grace upon whomever He chooses from among His servants. Consequently, they incurred wrath upon wrath. Such disbelievers have deserved humiliating retribution.
Why did they have to take these verses?
this assignment.
Anyway, these are quite relevant to what is
happening to us these days.
[2:90]  Miserable indeed is what they sold their souls for, disbelieving in God's revelations...
God tells them "a messenger will come after
all the prophets," but they disbelieve.
It's very clear in the Quran.
And this is why they're so dumb in the sense
that they don't say anything.
They are very quiet.
They don't know what to say.
This is why they're getting their top leaders
to put their heads together, pat each other on the back,
and gang together to distort
the definition of prophet and messenger.
They don't believe God's revelations.
[2:90]  ....Out of sheer resentment that God should bestow
His grace upon whomever He chooses from among His servants.
Where is Douglas? Is Douglas here?
Hi, Douglas.
Douglas was rooming in a hotel in one of the conferences of the probably social scientists, Muslim social scientists.
And this is one of the top leaders of the
Muslims in America. Ilyas Ba-Yunus is his name.
And he rejected the mathematical miracle of
the Quran, this Ba-Yunus.
And then the next day, Douglas is gonna correct me if I'm
wrong, the next day,
Douglas realized that he actually knows the miracle and believes
in it.
So, Douglas asked him. You take it from there. "Why don't you recognize the miracle?" What did he say?
Douglas: I asked him why didn't he recognize the miracle.
Then, his response was "it didn't come from
one of us."
"It didn't come from one of us Muslim scholars,
religious scholars."
He said that Rashad didn't have the right
place.
Dr. Khalifa: "He's not one of us."
Douglas: "He's not one of us. And he's not a religious scholar. He's not a Mulla."
Dr. Khalifa: Mulla.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is exactly what this verse is saying.
[2:90]...out of sheer resentment...
Not because it is not the truth, or because they do not recognize it, or because they don't understand it.
But it's simply
[2:90] ...out of sheer resentment that God should bestow His grace upon whomever He chooses from among His servants. Consequently, they incurred wrath upon wrath. Such disbelievers have deserved humiliating retribution.
I want to share with you some other verses
related to this.
Yep, they're human beings.
Ego.
Ego is the big disaster.
Edip:
وَكَذَٰلِكَ فَتَنَّا بَعْضَهُم بِبَعْضٍۢ لِّيَقُولُوٓا۟ أَهَـٰٓؤُلَآءِ مَنَّ ٱللَّهُ عَلَيْهِم
(6:53) مِّنۢ
Dr. Khalifa: 21:36. Yeah, that's a good one too.
Edip: 6:53.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Let's look at 21:36. 21:36
Because it is similar to that statement that
they told Douglas.
Under the subtitle "All Messengers Ridiculed."
36,
[21:36]  When those who disbelieve see you, they ridicule you: "Is this the one who talks about your idols?" They totally disregard the message of the Most Gracious.
This is not the verse that I wanted to
show you, but it's related.
Edip: 6:53
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, there's another one.
(25:41) إِلَّا هُزُوًا أَهَـٰذَا ٱلَّذِى بَعَثَ ٱللَّهُ رَسُولًا
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Let's look at 25:41.
25:41 must be the one I had in mind.
They're very similar words.
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: 25:41, again, messengers ridiculed.
[25:41]  When they saw you, they always ridiculed you. "Is this the one chosen by God to be a messenger?"
[25:42]  "He almost diverted us from our gods, if it were not that we steadfastly revered them."
Counsel for preservation of the finality of
prophethood.
[25:42] ...They will certainly find out, when they see the retribution, who are the real strayers from the path.
Oh my gosh, 43.
[25:43]  Have you seen the one whose god is his ego? Are you going to be his advocate?
So, this is the reason why they cannot accept
a human being.
And this is exactly why God said "if I sent
an angel..."
God said "even if I sent an angel as a messenger, I will send him in the form of a human being, and I would confuse them as they are confused."
"Miserable indeed," number 90, back to.
[2:90]  Miserable indeed is what they sold their souls for, disbelieving in God's revelations out of sheer resentment that God should bestow His grace upon whomever He chooses from among His servants. Consequently, they incurred wrath upon wrath. Such disbelievers have deserved humiliating retribution.
Let me share a couple more verses with you,
so we can cover the subject,
and hopefully not see it for another long time.
43:32.
Then, we'll move on. 43:32.
Probably 31. We'll look at it.
Okay, 31.
Muhammad Ridiculed
[43:31]  They said, "If only this Quran was sent down through another man from the two communities (Mecca or Medina) who is prominent!"
They didn't like the Prophet Muhammad.
And these very same people would have done
the same thing then.
Now, 32 says,
[43:32]  Are they the ones who assign your Lord's mercy? We have assigned their shares in this life, raising some of them above others in ranks, in order to let them serve one another. However, the mercy from your Lord is far better than any material they may hoard.
But the same idea that applies to material
things also applies to God's mercy as far as...
God blessed us to be believers. They
cannot do anything if they resent that.
91, back to page 14.
[2:91]  When they are told, "You shall believe in what GOD had sent down herein," they say, "We believe only in what was sent down to us." They reject subsequent revelations, even if it is the truth from their Lord, and even though it confirms what they have! Say, "if you did believe in the revelations given to you, why then did you kill God's prophets, if you are truthful?"
As you know, the prophets of Israel, almost
all of them were killed by the children of Israel.
"Lessons from Israel" 92.
[2:92]  Moses went to you with profound miracles, yet you worshiped the calf in his absence, and you turned wicked.
[2:93]  Also, we made a covenant with you, as we raised Mount Sinai above you, saying, "You shall uphold the commandments we have given you, strongly, and listen." But they said, "We hear, but we disobey." Their hearts became filled with adoration for the calf, due to their disbelief. Say, "Miserable indeed is what your faith dictates upon you, if you do have any faith."
94,
[2:94]  Say, "If the abode of the Hereafter is really reserved for you at GOD, to the exclusion of all other people, then you should long for death, if you are truthful."
[2:95]  They never long for it, because of what their hands have sent forth. GOD is fully aware of the wicked.
I wanna go back to verse 92.
[2:92]  Moses went to you with profound miracles, yet you worshiped the calf in his absence, and you turned wicked.
Because this again is a continuation of the
Khutba today on how bad the humans are and
how fortunate we are.
We must thank God and say "Alhamdu Lillah."
Thank him profusely for guiding us.
This will be our prayer, IN SHAA ALLAH, in Heaven
as you know from the Quran.
We're gonna spend eternity saying "thank
God for guiding us."
I wanted, actually, to say this in the Khutba, but I
forgot.
Do you know how many people believed in Moses
after all the miracles,
after parting the Red Sea?
120,000 people, they estimate, watched the Red Sea part.
Did anybody see a hill of water?
There were 2 hills of water on the sides and...
And these people walked between two hills of water.
And if you saw the movie, it made a very good
approximation.
the Ten Commandments.
Cecil B. DeMille did a good job there.
And then after they crossed, Pharaoh and his
army goes behind them and they drown and die,
the enemies before their eyes. God says in the Quran "before your eyes." They saw this
and many other miracles.
So, how many people believed at the very end
when they reached their destination and Moses said
"now go into Jerusalem." And they said
"there are people there, we don't wanna go and fight with them.
You and your Lord go and
fight. We're going to sit right here."
Two people.
Moses, Aaron, and two people.
That's how bad the humans are.
Now fortunately, Sura 5, verse 23. This is what it tells us.
Just two people believed with Moses.
Now, I don't want you to be too scared because
this is not applicable, the same principle
is not applicable to us. We thank God for
it that God assigned us to this generation.
We are very fortunate because the last Sura
in the Quran revealed, Sura 110, is 19 words and talks about
entering God's religion in great numbers.
And this is applicable to us. The first verse
is 19 letters and the whole Sura is 19 words.
But at the same time, don't be lax. You must
watch your ego because making it, as you see and
worshipping God alone and killing our ego is the
greatest triumph.
We've made quite a few mistakes. Initially,
when Satan wanted to be a god, we made a big mistake.
When God gave us another chance, we
made a bigger mistake.
And you've seen the, you've seen the proportion of how bad the humans are.
And it's all ego from Satan's ego to our ego.
This is what exiled us from God's kingdom
We're in exile from God's kingdom because
of our ego and if we don't kill this ego,
we will continue to be eternally exiled. Now, this
is our last chance in this world. It's our chance.
God is giving us a taste of what
Hell is like. This is halfway house to Hell.
It is.
It's amazing how many problems there
are in this world that we're seeing.
Yes?
A man: ..... using your will to suppress Satan and his ideas in your head.
A man: Can you ask for repent for me? Sometimes, I ask for repent for a sin or (unintelligible) or a lie or something. Then, I find how Satan brings it back.
Dr. Khalifa: This is his job. He's doing his job.
Dr. Khalifa: He uses, he uses reverse psychology. He tells you "you're
bad. You're bad."
A man: .... but I don't know whether to, he uses my ego not in the negative sense. If I... Satan (unintelligible) a week then I know it continues. Then, I will fight with it.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, what you need to say to Satan is that you believe God, when He says
"repentance wipes out the sins
and turns them into credits." And don't let Satan
trick you into, into saying that, or giving you a guilt complex
over an old sin or a new sin.
A man: You know, it's not that... that's one aspect. (unintelligible) the future.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Then, I continued to strongly to grow in righteousness.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: I mean, I find myself trying to stop mind and Satan, cause I don't... you know, I know like I made a mistake but I don't wanna do it again so...
Dr. Khalifa: This is what repentance is all about. You pledge that you'll never do it again but being a human, you probably will do it again a few times
until you realize that the price is too high. The pinch is too painful
or the price is too high. Then, you'll... God knows
God will guide you. God says... God gives you the means to fight Satan and they are worshipping God regularly.
You must maintain the Five Prayers, the Fasting of Ramadan.
You must be conscious of God, the commemoration of God every chance you get.
God must be on your mind the majority of the
time.
Because one of the Khutbas that you missed
was "who is your god?"
And the answer is "whatever you're thinking
of most of the time, that's your god."
So, God gives us guidelines in the Quran as
to how to keep God in our mind the majority of the time.
Like saying "IN SHAA ALLAH, Mã Shã Allãh, Alhamdu Lillah, Subhan Allah" in English or Arabic or in any language, as long as you think about God most of the time.
So, reading the Quran... you have to read the Quran every day, at least two pages every day.
I know you do that. Where is your copy of the new Quran?
I don't wanna embarrass you. We have
copies here.
A man: I know. I just wanted to
Dr. Khalifa: Ok.
A man: I just wanted to understand the fact that we're responsible for saying "Astaghfirullah."
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: The way I say it is correct?
Dr. Khalifa: Yep.
92. Lessons From Israel. We did that. 93. Ok. So, we're talking about Moses
and 120,000
out of them, only two believed.
And the other half of the Khutba today was
how fortunate we are in that we are the generation that
God showed us the miracle of the Quran based on the number 19, and the last Sura revealed to the Quran is 19 words
and that it applies to our generation.
We thank God for that.
Let us read it. 110.
Sura 110 is in page what?
Because it applies to us.
603. Page 603, Sura 110 is "Triumph."
The greatest triumph is to denounce our crime
and believe in God alone and worship him alone. Last Sura revealed.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[110:1]  When triumph comes from GOD, and victory.
19 letters in Arabic.
[110:2]  You will see the people embracing GOD's religion in throngs.
[110:3]  You shall glorify and praise your Lord, and implore Him for forgiveness. He is the Redeemer.
So, this is the good news.
We just have to be careful not to blow it
this time. We blew it before a few times.
This is our last chance, and we better not
blow it.
I want to complete the picture for you that
ego, like I mentioned in the Khutba today,
is not that somebody comes and slaps you in
the face and you turn the other cheek.
This is, this is not relevant to your spiritual salvation.
We're talking about ego as far as God is concerned.
We must kill our ego and that we have to do
the Five Prayers, and regardless of what the people think, for example.
Fast the month of Ramadan, regardless
of what the people think.
The people will not put you in Heaven or Hell. They will not save you.
God is the One who will put you in Heaven, IN SHAA ALLAH.
God is the One who will save you.
God is the One who controls your kidneys and lungs, controls your health, your happiness. Directly, God says that in Sura 54.
It says "God is the One who controls your happiness
or misery."
(53:43) وَأَنَّهُۥ هُوَ أَضْحَكَ وَأَبْكَىٰ
God is... This is the Arabic.
Very clearly, God controls your happiness.
Nothing else, your friends, your relatives,
your parents, your children.
Nobody controls your happiness or misery.
God is the only One who controls happiness.
Therefore, if you are wise or intelligent,
you don't care what people say.
You worship God and you don't care who blames
you for it.
One of the descriptions of the believers in
the Quran "they don't worry about the blaming of the blamers."
(5:54) لَا يَخَافُونَ لَوْمَةَ لَآئِمٍۢ
لَوْمَةَ لَآئِمٍۢ
blaming of the blamers
You don't care about any blame.
It's very important not to blow it this time.
What?
I'll give you the...
(5:54) لَوْمَةَ لَآئِمٍۢ
It's so difficult. Where did you find it?
Just look at خَافُ
Edip: 5:54
Dr. Khalifa: 5:54? How did you do that?
5:54, Martha.
5:54 says,
[5:54]  O you who believe, if you revert from your religion, GOD will substitute in your place people whom He loves and they love Him. People who are humble with the believers, but stern with the disbelievers, and will strive in the cause of GOD without fear of any blamer.
There's, there's another verse also that is even clearer
than this, but this is good enough.
I'm glad we read this verse here.
[5:54]  O you who believe, if you revert from your religion,...
You know, when you shy away and you don't practice your religion, this is reverting.
[5:54]  .....GOD will substitute in your place people whom He loves....
God doesn't care.
Only if you believe that He cares about you.
[5:54]  .....GOD will substitute in your place people whom He loves and they love Him. People who are humble with the believers, and stern with the disbelievers,...
This is what I was talking about "if somebody
slaps you in the face."
You know, with the believers, you're a pussycat.
But with the disbelievers, you're a lion.
It takes killing the ego to be humble with
the believers.
And you don't fear any blamer.
[5:54]  .....Such is GOD's blessing; He bestows it upon whomever He wills. GOD is Bounteous, Omniscient.
Let's go to 97. Gabriel Mediates the Revelation
Yes, sir.
A man: The verse "we raised Mount Sinai above you" (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Physically, physically raised the mountain on top of them like an umbrella.
Yep. That's one of the miracles.
They've seen miracles. Only two believed in the end.
They're so bad.
I mean, God raised the mountain on top of
them as a sign that He is speaking to them
and made a covenant with them, the ten commandments.
I don't think it is in the Old Testament.
Some of the miracles disappeared, probably
they didn't believe it or they just dropped out for some reason.
I don't remember seeing it.
Dr. Khalifa: What do you wanna say?
Edip: The raising mountain can be in a way that
we made mountains that gives you shadow.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no. It says,
(7:171) كَأَنَّهُۥ ظُلَّةٌۭ
Dr. Khalifa: like umbrella.
Edip: Oh, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Edip: We discussed this (unintelligible). I didn't get this that umbrella.
Dr. Khalifa: See how difficult it is to believe? Edip is wondering if it is some other raising.
Edip: No, no.
A man: We were going over the Turkish translation.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: He was, so he translated right. I didn't (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: umbrella. Yes.
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: In another place, God said "I raised the mountain
on top of them like an umbrella." See, how the umbrella covers you?
Edip: I can't believe it.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, it was another miracle.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a miracle and it's also like a gun to
your head.
Edip: In the desert, they need shadow.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Who's this?
What did you say, Donna? I'm sorry.
Yes, yes, exactly.
Twice in the Quran, it is mentioned.
It can be also the day of the umbrella.
یوم ظُلَّةٌۭ
It's a good... do you have it in Turkish? ظُلَّةٌۭ. ظُلَّةٌۭ. Shadow?
Edip: (unintelligible) yes.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: 97.
Gabriel Mediates the Revelation
[2:97]  Say, "Whoever is an enemy of Gabriel should know that he has revealed this (Quran) into your heart, in accordance with GOD's will, confirming previous scriptures, and providing guidance and good news for the believers."
[2:98]  If one opposes GOD, His angels, His messengers,
Gabriel and Michael, then GOD opposes the disbelievers.
What a trade.
99.
[2:99]  We have sent down to you clear revelations, and only the wicked will reject them.
[2:100]  Is it not a fact that whenever they make a covenant, some of them will violate it? Indeed, most of them do not believe.
Proof of Disbelief.
When a messenger came from God,...
[2:101]  When a messenger from God went to them confirming what they have, some followers of the scripture disregarded GOD's scripture behind their backs, as if they never had any scripture.
Now, if this is applicable to the Jews, for
example, why did GOD put it here in the Quran?
Because all the interpretation and understanding
is that this is directed to the Jews, which is perfectly alright.
Dr. Khalifa: But why did God put it here? It's for us to read, right?
A man: Sure.
Dr. Khalifa: And to learn from this, and because this will be done by so-called Muslims. This is exactly what's happening today.
[2:101]  When a messenger from God went to them confirming what they have, some followers of the scripture...
This includes Jews, Christians and Muslims.
[2:101]  ....disregarded GOD's scripture behind their backs, as if they never had any scripture.
The announcement that I mentioned today at
the Khutba does not have the name of God in it whatsoever.
It does not have IN SHAA ALLAH. It does not follow
the Quran. There is no Quran in it at all, and anyone can look at it.
So, they completely disregard God's scripture.
God tells you "you must say "God willing" when
you say "we will do something.""
And when we wrote about our conference, for
example, we said "IN SHAA ALLAH." We said "God willing."
Because the Quran dictates that as a commandment.
You must say "God willing" if you're gonna
talk about the future.
And let the people...Ok. This is where you don't
feel the blaming of any blamer.
If they're gonna laugh at you because you
said "God willing," let them.
I mean, what will happen to you if they laugh
at you?
They cannot control your happiness or health.
So, you say it with courage and enthusiasm,
whether it is your boss or your professor.
Yes.
Right.
Yes, exactly.
In fact, this is the whole idea.
A woman: ....remember God when we're busy.
Dr. Khalifa: You're delivering a message when you do that.
Dr. Khalifa: You're reminding the people that there is
a God, because they say "wait a minute."
You know, he's just saying to a guy in
the market.
"I'll come back for the tomatoes, God willing,
in two hours."
And they will, they will, they will...
This reminds them that there is a God.
You're doing the job. And you're benefiting your
own soul.
So, they completely disregard the scripture.
102. Witchcraft.
[2:102]  They pursued what the devils told them concerning
the powers of Solomon.
Remember moving the palace from one place
to place, 2,000 miles or something, 1,000 miles?
Of course, this is one thing that we know
about, but there were other powers that the jinns did for Solomon.
There were movies made about Solomon, and the treasures of Solomon, where they shot some of these superhuman things.
[2:102]  ...Solomon, however, was not a disbeliever....
In other words, he did not abuse the power
that God put at his disposal.
[2:102]  ....while the devils are disbelievers. Thus, they taught the people witchcraft.
What is witchcraft and magic?
It's using the jinns.
It's no big deal, actually.
I think you go to the library and learn
magic, witchcraft. There are many books on witchcraft.
In fact, you don't need any books.
You can sit in a room and talk to the jinns until they respond to you if you want to get in trouble, because they are in the same room with you.
And if you talk to them long enough, some rascal jinn passing by who wants to have some fun will respond to you.
And like Sura 72 tells us, they will give you trouble in the end because they're much more powerful than you. I can tell you that.
So, you can imagine an invisible lion passing
by and you're trying to pet him or something.
But he's invisible.
They're much, much more powerful than the
lion.
So, it doesn't make sense that they will be
your slave.
They will fool you for a while. They will do certain things for you.
And this is why those people that you see
on the TV, they don't last.
Because jinns will not serve them for too
long.
Maybe a few months and then they disappear. Otherwise, it would have been a big hit.
And I remember one of them, when the election
was between Carter and Reagan,
this ESP fellow, using the jinns, was on the Today
Show two weeks before the elections.
And he gave Jane Pauley, is that her name?
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: He gave her an envelope, sealed envelope.
And he said "this envelope will have who won the elections and how many votes," if it is Reagan or Carter, and how many votes.
"I will come back on the election. The next day of the election, we'll open the envelope and you're gonna see in it the winner and the number of votes."
Unfortunately, I didn't see that program,
but he probably came and they probably opened
the envelope and saw that the winner was Reagan
and how many votes. So, how did that happen?
They show you on TV somebody who's standing
on a stage and some person in the audience
will take his wallet out and this fellow on the stage will read what's in the wallet, the money, the driver's license.
How does he do this?
He's using jinns.
Now, this is fantastic, right?
And it should be a show that will last for
10 years, but they don't.
Because the jinn will go read the wallet and
will come and whisper it in his ears and he read the
thing and everybody will be
impressed.
But next week, when he wants to use the jinn
again, the jinn will say "wait a minute, who do you think you are?"
And they will not cooperate.
Sura 72.
Usually it is the last time you see them on
the TV.
The jinn is having fun, you know, national TV, you know, impressing the audience and all that, but they don't last.
For one thing, they can take a trip that is
10 light years away, then they lose their cooperating entity.
So, I wanna go back to 102.
[2:102]  ....Solomon was not a disbeliever, while the devils
are disbelievers. Thus, they taught the people witchcraft that
was sent down through the two angels of Babel, Haroot and Maroot.
[2:102]  ....These two did not divulge such knowledge without
pointing out that "This is a test. You shall not abuse such knowledge."
So, God actually sent the knowledge to the planet earth as part of the test to see who's gonna use it, who's gonna abuse it.
And as you know, a lot of people do abuse
it.
You should come to Egypt and see what they
do.
[2:102] ......But the people used it in such evil schemes as the breaking up of marriages. They can never harm anyone against the will of God. They learn only what hurts them, not what benefits them,
[2:102] ......and they knew full well that whoever practices such evil will have no share in the Hereafter. Miserable indeed is what they sold their souls for, if they only knew.
So, when you hear about this phenomenon in
the newspaper, you understand exactly what is happening.
103.
[2:103]  Had they believed and led a righteous life,
the reward from GOD would have been far better, if they only knew.
Twisting the Words of Supplication
[2:104]  O you who believe, do not say, "Raa'ena"* (be our shepherd). You should say, "Unzurna" (watch over us), and listen. The disbelievers have incurred a painful retribution.
You can generalize this. If there are words that sound like bad words,
you don't have to use them.
It's better to avoid them.
So, this doesn't apply to people who do not
speak Arabic, but it will apply as a general rule.
I was talking to somebody the other day about... I was talking to Robert actually, about university degrees and so on, and I repeated the word BS a lot.
But this word BS sounds like a bad word in
the general language.
"Oh, you can get a BS by doing this and that,
and studying this and that."
It means a Bachelor's degree.
Dr. Khalifa: But BS has other meanings. So, it is better to avoid using those words.
Cisco: But it's actually what it is.
Cisco: It's BS.
Cisco: Because I mean...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, tell us about it, Cisco.
Cisco: You know, because people could be graduating in science,
and they could run a business.
Or it could be the opposite way.
Cisco: They could be graduating in business and going to work in a field application which is BS.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: It's a bunch of BS.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm just giving an example.
Where is Robert? I thought Robert was here.
Oh, Robert is there. Ok.
105. Jealousy Condemned
[2:105]  Neither the disbelievers among the followers
of the scripture...
like Ba-Yunus
[2:105]  ...nor the idol worshippers wish to see any blessings come your way from your Lord. However, GOD showers His blessings upon whomever He chooses. GOD possesses infinite grace.
I think I'm very proud of Apamea and Naghmeh, for example, because they went through so much jealousy and people harassing them about going to Masjid Tucson.
But they steadfastly persevered.
And this is why they're in for lots of rewards, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Hey, Naghmeh, how come every time I call Edip's house, you answer the phone?
I mean, your sister is married now.
Mã Shã Allãh
I love it, though. It's beautiful.
Naghmeh: It's her voice that sounds like
mine.
Dr. Khalifa: Is that right?
Maghmeh: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: See, they are cooperating.
Well then, how do you explain it when Apamea is here
and I call and you answer?
Well, as long as you don't keep Edip on the couch
outside in the living room, it's Ok.
106.
‘Alaykum Al-Salaam
A man: (unintelligible) Haroot
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They brought the knowledge of witchcraft to
the planet Earth.
And they taught a few people.
And they spread it around until it was imported
to Boston, Massachusetts.
How long ago was it? A hundred years?
The witches?
Yes.
It's just, you know, God sends information
to the Earth through angels.
And Haroot and Maroot happen to be the angels
who carried the knowledge about witchcraft, here.
Because it's a definite science. I mean, you have to stand somewhere and draw a triangle and throw some chicken...
....do that will lure them.
A man: Some patients, not a lot of, some patients in psychiatric facilities have called it one jinn.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: In any psychiatric facilities, they become victims.
And when you walk around in the buildings,
you can definitely see they're possessed. And
anyone you see (unintelligible) everyday.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, we do hear about all these phenomena a lot but
there are people who actually practice witchcraft and that originally came down through these two angels, Haroot and Maroot. So, you know everything about it. Question?
Edip: Rashad, I wanna say something about "Raa'ena."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, my goodness
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
Edip: About word "Raa'ena" in verse 104, be our shepherd,
the word by itself is not a dirty word, but
the meaning...
Dr. Khalifa: Hebrew it was. Do you know Hebrew?
Edip: I don't know Hebrew.
Dr. Khalifa: So, how do you know it's not a dirty word?
Edip: Let me. My understanding, I don't know if it's correct
or not, "Raa'ena" means "be our shepherd" and
Edip: those people that who used this accept themselves as sheep and...
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Edip: This is...
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's in Sura 4, you see, if you look at 4:46...
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But let's not look. I don't wanna waste time on this one. But it's just, in the Hebrew language, it sounds like a dirty word.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Dr. Khalifa: "Raa'ena" is Arabic. But you can say an Arabic word
that's dirty in English and vice versa. Yes
Why are we laughing, Emily?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Naghmeh. Cause I remember your incident
with Ihsan, Naghmeh.
Naghmeh: I didn't know.
A woman: I know that nothing happens because of (unintelligible).
And here, because they used their evil in breaking of the marriages. They can never harm anyone against the will of God.
So, (unintelligible) people (unintelligible) God willed it to happen. I mean, I don't understand like how that could be used.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. You're forcing me to give you a real life story.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, there's a person who uses witchcraft and tried to harm me in this way and the jinn, that was supposed to come and
hurt me, came here and my... we all have guards,
angels.
And this was against the will of God. So, the angels told the jinn "what are you
here for?"
He said "we're here to hit Rashad."
He said "ok, you go back and hit the person who sent you."
And the jinn did and sure enough that
person called on the machine here and she was almost dying.
So, it backfired on her. But this is an example of "they cannot harm anyone against the will of God." Did that confuse you more?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. This person practiced witchcraft from,
from a country that is famous for witchcraft.
And she was trying to stop me. So, she practiced witchcraft on me but what happened was that the jinn that was supposed to carry out that,
since it is against God's will, I didn't deserve it, I didn't do anything wrong on that day, on that day,
the jinn was sent back and did that thing to that person and she almost died. And we have a few witnesses.
A woman: Are we talking about real witchcraft?
Dr. Khalifa: Real. This is real witchcraft. I'm telling you. She almost died. She
was paralyzed.
What country? Haiti. Haiti.
Haiti is full of voodoo. And voodoo, for example,
is that real? Is voodoo real?
It is real and it is jinn. When you make a
doll that looks like Muhtesem, and you get a pin,
and the jinn... now the jinns, as you know, are
very fast. They see that you're poking,
pulling his ear, for example, so they go and pull his
ear. This is the mechanism of it.
It's real. I mean, this is what the Quran is teaching us. Yes.
A woman: So, if
two people get divorced, does that, you know,... I mean,...
Dr. Khalifa: Well, everything, ultimately, is the will of God. Ok. But I want you to understand this that bad things are from us.
Good things are from God.
For example, I use the example of the fire. If you turn the stove on, it is God's law that if you put your finger in the fire, it will hurt, right?
It's God's law. So, it is the will of God that
if you put your finger in the fire, it will hurt.
But if you use the fire to cook your
burned rice, the Iranian people burn rice at the bottom,
they don't know how to cook rice.
You can use the, you can use the fire...
A woman: (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible) their faces (unintelligible).
A man: I know the Persians (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's my favorite part, the burned rice.
Dr. Khalifa: You know, at first, they were saying "the dumb guy, you know, he doesn't think we do it on purpose."
But anyway, so you can use the fire to cook your food
or to burn your finger.
So, if you use it to cook the food, it's from God. If you burn your
finger, it's from you because you decided to put your finger in the fire.
But not every
people who are divorced are because of witchcraft.
However, they do use witchcraft for this.
If it is in accordance with God's will, if these people are out of God's protection, the jinns will bother them.
But you are... when you are in God's protection, nothing can touch you. They cannot touch you.
A woman: But what if individuals have tried to, you know, hurt, you know, two other people and they were hurt for a while and then they got better and then the other person (unintelligible) on them.
You know, and they were ultimately the ones (unintelligible). They were hurt, you know for the time being.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: I don't if it was witchcraft or not but whatever...
Dr. Khalifa: That was in accordance with God's will, they were not protected at the time for some reason.
But this day, they can repent any time. They can join God's protection
any time. Then, the jinns who are bothering them will not be able to do anything anymore.
When you're in God's Kingdom nothing can touch you.
This is the message that we've been
living it. We've been living it for 11-12 years now.
So, our confidence is increasing. It is now absolute when God tells you "I guarantee you perfect happiness, perfect health perfect
wealth," God means it and He does it.
So, using the jinns... remember the angels who are guarding
you are much stronger. But if you're out of God's protection,
if you're a... the person is bad and is against God and an idol worshipper, the angels who are guarding him hate him.
So, when a jinn
comes to slap him on the face, they say "yeah, be my guest."
This is what the mechanism is
of being out of God's protection.
Right
They're not protected if they are not strong believers. It is... Most people are out of God's protection. It's basic.
And it takes discipline, strength and worshipping
God, practicing in order to be protected.
Remember the verses in Sura 41. It gives you the conditions
of being in God's protection.
Page 480.
Verse 30. It says,
[41:30]  Those who say: "Our Lord is GOD,"...
We say "our Lord is God alone." But that's not all.
[41:30]  ....then lead a righteous life,...
So, it takes discipline and work, worshipping God, the Five daily Prayers.
In fact, when you miss a Prayer, you're out
of God's protection even though you're a believer.
When you miss a Prayer, you're out
of God's protection but God puts limits though
on how much you pay, how hard the pinch is. We learn this very well from the Old Testament and the Quran
that God puts limits on the
jinns, Satan, your enemies.
So that you don't get more of a pinch than you deserve. So, when
you miss a Prayer, you get a pinch.
This is how we come to realize that God runs the world,
controls everything.
A woman: About the witchcraft, isn't it when you give credit, like, to stuff like the evil eye, I mean, I think people actually help burning incense for evil eye, like,...
Dr. Khalifa: This is all over the Middle East. Yes.
A woman: I mean, come on, this is (unintelligible)
It's kind of like witchcraft but you're giving the jinns the credit (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You are absolutely
right, and he knows that, too.
A woman: Oh, yeah, he knows that but (unintelligible). I thought they were crazy by burning incense, I'm like, (unintelligible) the baby. "What are you doing?"
A woman: And he's like "no." He didn't (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Right. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's funny how they... this is all over the world. They believe that. Yeah, all kinds of strange things
A woman: Yeah, (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: It had to be seven times, did you count?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm sure they did it seven
times anyway. Then, they took the baby. That was their grandchild.
Ok. The Ultimate Miracle: The Quran's Mathematical Code* 106.
[2:106]  When we abrogate any miracle, or cause it to be forgotten, we bring a better miracle, or at least an equal one. Do you not know that GOD is Omnipotent?
[2:107]  Do you not know that GOD possesses the kingship of the heavens and the earth; and you have none besides GOD as your Lord and Master?
[2:108]  Do you wish to demand of your messenger what was demanded of Moses before? Anyone who substitutes disbelief for belief has truly strayed off the right path.
The...
[2:106]  .....Do you not know that GOD is Omnipotent?
When this miracle, this mathematical miracle, this
long sheet on the wall over there, which is a very
tiny fraction of the miracle is just too awesome for words. And it's a very simple thing thing, but it teaches that God is Omnipotent.
I just, I can't describe it in words.
How can you manipulate the numbers in this way? The physical structure of the Quran 114 Suras, every Sura is a specific number of verses.
And you put these numbers in any combination, and it comes out a multiple of 19. It's almost a physical impossibility.
Of course, it is not a physical impossibility because we see it,
but for the humans and the jinns, it is a physical impossibility.
God's greatness is indescribable.
And God is telling us that those miracles of Moses and Jesus are nothing. God can bring better miracles.
[2:109]  Many followers of the scripture actually wished to revert you, now that you have believed, into disbelievers. This is due to jealousy on their part, after the truth has become evident to them. You shall pardon them, and leave them alone, until GOD issues His judgment. GOD is Omnipotent.
Those idol worshipping Sunnis, for example, they would rather see you a Christian or a Jew or an atheist than what you are now, a believer.
They would rather see you disbelieve. And this was reflected
very clearly when at the meeting in Los Angeles,
when this guy gave a research, a lecture, saying
that the Quran was hallucinations of Muhammad,
and I stood up. I stood up and I
gave the evidence that the Quran is from God.
Who did they attack?
Actually, they're same people who are meeting in Chicago next week. They attacked me. They didn't attack the other guy who said "the Quran is hallucination."
They attacked the guy who says "the Quran is from God."
They would rather see
me say "the Quran is hallucination of Muhammad."
So, the Quran is really accurate in describing
them. 110.
This is a commandment to you and me.
[2:110]  You shall observe the Contact Prayers (Salat) and give the obligatory charity (Zakat). Any good you send forth on behalf of your souls,...
Dr. Khalifa: ...will end up in your, what is it, PRA?
A woman: PRA.
Dr. Khalifa: PRA. Post Retirement Account.
[2:110]  ....you will find it at GOD. GOD is seer of everything you do.
Now, I know for a fact that it takes time to complete,
to do the Contact Prayers, all five of them.
But be sure you go, you move forward, you always
move forward.
For example, you may start by doing the Morning Prayer, especially the young people. You may start by doing the Morning Prayer, only.
But be sure that you move forward, not backwards. So next time, you do the Noon... the Morning and the Night Prayer.
That's two of them, for a while, for a few months, maybe.
And don't be discouraged that you cannot do
the others. Then, you do the Morning, the Night, and the Noon.
As long as you keep growing, you'll
do alright, but don't hear this commandment and ignore it.
[2:110]  You shall observe the Contact Prayers (Salat) and give the obligatory charity (Zakat).
You can't keep ignoring it. This is God
ordering you to do this, the Five Prayers.
This is really the minimum that we can do. And it helps you a lot. You come a long way towards having God as your god. Just the Five Prayers and you come a long way.
And as I mentioned repeatedly before, God wants the strong and
the disciplined in His Kingdom. He does not want the lazy ones.
God wants the strong and the disciplined who can do the Five Prayers. You must force your body to do the Five Prayers
every day. If you're not doing them, you're not being fair to yourself.
You're suffering too much, unnecessarily, because everything will be straighted in your life if you do the Five Prayers.
And you must be hard on yourself. Put your "self" on trial and tell yourself "you are bad, self. You must do the Five Prayers. Why don't you do the Five Prayers?"
You must keep after your self, until you do, carry out this commandment, 110.
But don't let Satan discourage you, as I said. As long as you move forward.
[2:110]  You shall observe the Contact Prayers (Salat) and give the obligatory charity (Zakat).
And this is, the rest of the
verse tells us that this is what you're depositing in your PRA.
This is what you benefit now. You
receive interest now, fringe benefits.
[2:110]  ....Any good you send forth on behalf of your souls, you will find it at GOD. GOD is seer of everything you do.
111.
[2:111]  They said, "No one will enter Paradise unless he is Jewish or Christian!" Such is wishful thinking on their part. Say, "Show us your proof, if you are truthful."
And the Muslims, so called Muslims, fall in the same trap. They say "the Jews and the Christians will not go to Heaven."
Well, the Quran tells us otherwise. It is... anyone
who worships God alone will make it to Heaven.
The criterion is to worship God alone. There's a book circulating in the United States now
that was written in Saudi Arabia. And in it, they say "if you meet a Christian or a Jew, you must ask them to repent. If they don't
repent, you must kill them."
This is in the book. Yes.
It's a book entitled "the Muslims believe."
Imagine that.
It's unbelievable, right? I mean, I don't blame you if you don't believe me. But this is true. You can come and read it for yourself. I have it. I have the review of it on my desk.
It's incredible.
Edip: Doctors.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Both of them. Yes.
The translator and the writer are both doctors
from WAMY, World Assembly of Muslim Youth.
Edip: I was a member of WAMY.
Dr. Khalifa: You were?
Dr. Khalifa: Edip used to be a member
of WAMY. Don't worry. We all were.
Edip: Ahmad (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, of course. He was the first president of...
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I know him very well.
112,
[2:112]  Indeed,...
Here's the answer.
[2:112]  ...those who devote themselves absolutely to GOD...
And it doesn't tell you if it's a Hindu or a Buddhist or a Muslim or what.
[2:112]  ....those who devote themselves absolutely to GOD alone, while leading a righteous life, will receive their recompense from their Lord; they have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.*
This is similar to the verse 62 that names names says "the Jews, the Christians, the converts, the Muslims, any of them, who devotes
themselves absolutely to God and lead a righteous life, they will
receive the recompense from their Lord. They have nothing to fear nor will they grieve."
The advantage that you have over the Jew or the Christian is that they lost the Contact Prayer.
You have the Contact Prayer. You have the complete message from God and you have the complete practices. Nothing was lost.
So, the difference is that it's like a person who's going to Boulder, Colorado without a map and a person who's going with a map. You have a map.
A woman: But they don't have the right map.
Dr. Khalifa: They have a map from 1800. They don't even have the map. They lost it. Sura 19.
So, God says "He will give them credit for any worship that they do but it is the hard way. It takes longer. They don't grow at the same as you do.
Because what you're following...
did you see the mathematical coding of Al-Fãtehah?
They don't have Al-Fãtehah. God gave us this
and it causes you to grow much faster, more efficiently.
But they're still... they get credit
for worshiping God alone.
113.
[2:113]  The Jews said, "The Christians have no basis," while the Christians said, "The Jews have no basis." Although they both read the scripture.
Not the same scripture. Both of them read the scripture.
[2:113]  ...those who possess no knowledge have uttered the same kind of utterances. GOD will judge them all on the Day of Resurrection, regarding their disputes.
What does this say?
It says,
[2:113]  The Jews said, "The Christians have no basis." The Christians said, "The Jews have no basis." Even though both read the scripture.
So, God is saying that you can reach God through either way
as long as you or they worship God alone,
devote yourself to God alone and lead a righteous life.
Did you say something?
Edip: I said "those who possess no knowledge have uttered the same kind of utterances." They're just Muslims today.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, sir?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, a few, quite a few. In fact, we passed... maybe coming up, and we passed a couple of them.
113. 114.
You Shall Frequent the Mosques
This is why we are here.
[2:114]  Who are more evil than those who boycott GOD's mosques, where His name is commemorated, and contribute to their desertion? These ought not to enter therein except fearfully. They have incurred humiliation in this life, and severe retribution in the Hereafter.
So, we must encourage each other to frequent the mosque. The Quranic study is a perfect example. Of course, the people who need this advice are not here.
[2:115]  To GOD belongs the east and the west; wherever you go there will be the face of GOD. GOD is Omnipresent, Omniscient.
You must also observe God wherever you may be,
in addition to coming to the mosque.
Gross Blasphemy
[2:116]  They said, "GOD has begotten a son!" Be He glorified; never! To Him belongs everything in the heavens and the earth; all are subservient to Him.
Of course as we increase, our knowledge increases
and we realize how vast our universe is,
and how vast the other universes are and that
they're all in God's hand.
With this knowledge, we realize how ridiculous
such a statement is.
It's like... it's not even like that, but it's
like saying "you're the father of a virus. Here's your son.
Go find an electronic microscope to see him,
your dear son."
"Don't you love your son? Right here, at the
tip of my finger," there are a few viruses probably.
So ridiculous.
[2:117]  He is the Initiator of the heavens and the earth: to have anything done, He simply says to it, "Be," and it is.
[2:118]  Those who possess no knowledge have said, "If only GOD could speak to us, or some miracle could come to us!" Others before them have uttered the same kind of utterances; their minds are similar. We do manifest the miracles for those who have attained certainty.
This is a very important principle.
When you attain certainty, you see miracles.
[2:119]  We have sent you* with the truth as a bearer of good news, as well as a warner. And you are not answerable for those who have incurred Hell.
I'm going to stop right here.
Dr. Sabahi, are you gonna take the Quranic
study next week?
Did you say only one? Huh?
Okay.
You don't wanna take the Quranic study as
well?
Oh, you will not be here?
Oh, okay.
Where is Laurie?
You didn't come last week, right?
You did?
Oh, I thought you had a football game or something.
In fact, I meant to call you the next morning.
Then, I forgot.
Oh, okay.
I thought I asked a few people, but anyway.
So, Laurie will give us the Quranic study
next week, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Are there any questions before we close this
study?
It's okay, any general questions.
Was it the...
Yes, it is Divine.
And it is Barã'ah (Ultimatum).
No.
It was Barã'ah until about a hundred years
ago, when they changed it.
So, what I'm doing here is taking everything back to the original, including the names of the Suras. The names of the Suras are Divine.
No, I didn't need to, because it is known
actually equally as Barã'ah and Tawbah, so I didn't need to, I didn't.
It probably does, probably does.
But we're not aware yet of it.
Because the names must stay the way they came
down.
Let me see. The numbers of the Suras, yes.
But the names...
Edip: I have some significant news, but it's not
all about the Suras.
Edip: There are some Suras that the names of the
Suras are related with some very interesting news.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm sure there are... I'm sure there will be, because everything in the Quran is mathematically coded.
So far we don't have anything established
yet.
Edip: But this Sura, according to also traditional
knowledge, also has two names.
It is Tawbah or Barã'ah. Some people use Barã'ah, but
it's also Barã'ah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, it is well known as Barã'ah and Tawbah,
but Tawbah is a strange name. It's a foreign name.
In fact, I see it here. We should have changed that to Arabic.
Sorry about that.
Yes.
In the next edition, I will change this Arabic
name also to Barã'ah.
Yes. I'm sure there is some mathematical basis
for it.
That's a good question.
The names of the Suras were divinely inspired.
This is why this is The Heifer (Al-Baqarah), for example,
and not anything else.
Even though there are many important subjects
in this Sura.
But if you look at the old books, all of them
say "Barã'ah," up to 100 years ago.
Then, this name Tawbah started to appear in less than 100-year-old books.
Any other questions?
Well, let us... We're celebrating Apamea's birthday today.
Edip: Did she born in two days?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, her birthday was in the middle of the
week, so she gets two Fãtehahs.
Edip: Mã Shã Allãh
Dr. Khalifa: Also, it's a good excuse to have some cake.
It's nobody's birthday until... October 12
is Gatut, this year.
The next birthday is October 12. That's
Gatut.
So,...
You didn't know that, did you?
Yes.
You want it for what? I forgot.
Very good.
Ok, this is Al-Fãtehah for Frank's trip. He have a good one.
And Al-Fãtehah for Apamea that may God give her a very happy year coming
up.
And maybe a little one at the end of that
year.
IN SHAA ALLAh
And every year to be even happier, every year
after that.
Al-Fãtehah
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (1:1)
Al hamdu Lillahi Rabbil ‘Alameen (1:2)
Arrahman Arraheem (1:3)
Maliki Yawm Eddeen (1:4)
Eyyaka Na’abudu Wa Eyyaka Nasta’aeen (1:5)
Ehdina Al-Serata Al-Mustaqeem (1:6)
Serata Al-Lazeena An’amta ‘Alayhim Ghayri Al-Maghdoobi ‘Alayhim Wa Laddaalleen (1:7)
Congratulations. God bless you.
Very fortunate. You're a fortunate believer. Mã Shã Allãh.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
In the name of GOD, Most Gracious, Most Merciful.
Congratulations for reading the Quran.
And congratulations on starting with the new
translation.
And I want to tell you right now that this
was made obsolete before it came out of the press.
Which is a very great sign that we must be
congratulated about.
Because we are advancing faster than the press
can work.
For example, you see, you see the title page,
down this is "Islamic Productions Tucson."
The next edition, "The United Submitters International, Tucson", for example, just to give you an idea of why this was obsolete before
it came out of the press.
And throughout the translation, "Islam" would
be "Submission." And "Muslim" will be "Submitter."
And the translation will be universalized.
It is not appropriate. This word, production,
is not appropriate.
Islam is Arabic. Production is English.
In Arabic, we call the Christian person Nasrani (نَصْرَانِي)
But when you say Christian productions, you don't say Nasrani productions. You say Christian productions. The whole thing is English.
Also, this is a stage. You can see that God
wants to put the whole world to test.
When the miracle of the Quran appeared first,
the title was "The Perpetual Miracle of Muhammad."
It was in Arabic
"(unintelligible) معجزة محمد"
And it was distributed as such.
I still have the labels as such, but the
Arabs and the Muslims still do not understand the miracle.
So, it is not the current excuse that Rashad Khalifa has
gone crazy or whatever excuses they used are not true, are not accepted.
They don't... Even if they say "we don't accept this miracle
of the Quran because Rashad Khalifa is crazy." They cannot do that.
Because, initially, the miracle was titled
"The Miracle of Muhammad, The Perpetual Miracle of Muhammad"
which is true because it came
through the Prophet Muhammad.
God sent it to the world through the Prophet, in the Quran,
and was there the whole time.
And still the Arabs, as you see from the last issue, mainly the Arabs could not understand it, were not permitted to understand it.
And then, it progressed. God willed that it progresses and it became universalized. It became just (unintelligible) the miracle.
And it didn't matter how they accepted it
or not.
Same with the first translation and with this
translation, they cannot say "this is off", you see.
They can look on the spine of the book and it says "Islamic Productions" on there and also it says "the Only Religion acceptable to God is Islam."
I mean, just go flip a couple of pages, see "proclaiming
one religion for all the people."
And you can see the translation in the first
rectangle saying "the Only Religion acceptable to God is Islam."
So, even though it is very clearly in harmonizing with their language, you will note pretty soon that they don't accept this translation
because God wants to prove something, prove
their defiance, regardless of... Even if you agree with them.
Because even if you agree with them and you present the truth to them of worshipping God alone and upholding the word of God alone, they're just not having it in their hearts.
And God will not allow them, does not permit them, as we read in many, many verses in the Quran. God does not permit them to accept the truth.
In Sura 43, we're told that on the Day of Judgment, they will say to guardian of Hell "Let your Lord finish us off."
And the Guardian of Hell, the angel of Hell
will tell them "No, you're gonna stay like this forever."
"We have brought the truth to you, we have
presented the truth to you, but most of you hate the truth."
Which is true, they really hate the truth.
It is something that was incomprehensible.
How can people hate the truth? But it happens, they demonstrate it continuously, they hate the truth.
And they will hate anything to do with God, or
anything to do with the truth.
And they want to stay away from it as far
as possible. And this is documented in the Quran.
So, this is why, I'm just trying to explain to
you why this was obsolete before it came out of the press.
It's also, every step of this book, every step was guided by God. And we had many, many signs that we'll be talking about in the future, from now on.
But I want to share with you the last sign
about this book.
I was supposed to pick it up from the press
on the 18th, Friday the 18th, which is the last day of the week.
And this was done 50 days before that time.
We submitted the originals and they put the schedule and it was scheduled to be released on the 18th, which is the end of the week.
On the 17th, when I called, I said "OK, I'm
coming to pick it up."
They were very apologetic and they said they will work the weekend because the book will be finished on the 19th, which is a Saturday.
So, this is another vital sign because there
are so many departments.
As you see from the book, it's a big printer.
It is the same printer that prints books for the University of Arizona Press and to some of the most famous universities around the country.
And there are many departments and every department has its own problems and delays and so on, but the book was finished on the 19th.
And on the 19th, I was in Washington, D.C.
and I was driving with Ihsan.
I just decided to be a tourist.
So, I went out to the tourist areas, Lincoln
Memorial, Washington Memorial, the Capitol and so on.
And we were just leaving Lincoln Memorial,
driving back to Ihsan's house.
And all of a sudden, all the license plates... now this may be superstition, but God gives us messages through our superstitions.
I want you to know this, too. From my experience, and probably you all had these experiences.
If you were superstitious, for example, that
if you wake up in the morning and see a butterfly
standing in the northern corner, northwest
corner of your house, in the roof, this means you'll have a good day.
Ok. This is superstition.
Then, God will speak to you through that superstition
and you'll have a good day.
If God wants to tell you so, He'll send you a butterfly in the northwest
corner of the roof of your house. That's what you know.
So anyway, about 1 o'clock on Saturday, 19th of August, and I was driving back from Lincoln Memorial, and all of a sudden
all the license plates around us, almost all of them were divisible by 19 on both sides people parked and in the cars parked on both sides.
And it was really a very strange phenomenon.
I've never in my life seen so many divisible
numbers of license plates.
I said "what is going on? What is happening?" I said "what is this?"
And then we came to a street that is only
about 6 or 7 blocks from Ihsan's house called Reed.
The street, the name of the street is Reed. And in the corner is Perpetual Savings. We have also two people from Washington, D.C.
Do you know the area, Gale and Mobile?
Perpetual Savings on Reed Street, and the
first car in front of us that's gonna turn left is number 114.
I said "this is it. The book is being finished now. So, I'm gonna check with the press."
I said "this is it. It must be that the book is being finished
now."
And sure enough, when I went there, I said "I'm curious. When did you finish yesterday? You know, You worked on the weekend. I really appreciate it. What time did you finish?"
"Oh, between 1 and 2 o'clock."
I said "hmm, we knew that."
So, that was the last sign.
So anyway, every step of this, when you find
any typing errors or anything, you can be
sure that they are designed by God, because God creates loopholes for the disbelievers who insist on going to Hell.
And so every step of this book was designed by
God.
And this fits in with Edip's Khutba today,
by the way.
If you find any, already Emily found a minor
mistake where I forgot to put Arabic, the Arabic word next to it.
So, all these things are guided by God.
I think it is in the beginning of Sura 7. I wanted...
The first verse I wanted to look at in the
new translation is in Sura 7 at the beginning, or 6.
6 or 7.
I'm gonna find out exactly the Sura... the Sura and the
verse number.
Dr. Khalifa: Give me just a second. I'll find it. Right. Yeah.
Edip: Definitely.
Dr. Khalifa: Sura 6, verse 9. Ok? Let's read it together.
Sura 6, verse 9.
The top of page 129.
Subtitle is "Requirements of the Test."
And it says,
[6:9]  Had we sent an angel, we would have sent him in the form of a man, and we would have kept them just as confused as they are confused now.
So, that was Edip's Khutba today.
God said "Even if I sent an angel, I will
send him in the form of a human being,
a goofy one, and confuse the heck out of them
just as they are confused now."
So, it is a requirement that God... number 10
says,
[6:10]  Messengers before you have been ridiculed. Those who mocked them had incurred the consequences of their ridiculing.
It's because the disbelievers God creates
these loopholes for the disbelievers to perfect it.
If God sends an angel, the whole world will
believe.
If there is an angel who is mighty and strange looking, has these powers and so on, what is the big deal? What is the test?
But we are fortunate in that sense that, that
we are passing very difficult tests at very
special times and I am passing them along with you
and telling you because more than
90% of the time, I am required, just as you are
to believe certain things that I did
not know before in the past.
So, I know it is very difficult.
In fact, I probably was the, the most lax of power among... there were many of you who may have more courage than me because for eight years I was a secret, a secret agent.
Even now I can't bring out the word.
So, it is just as difficult. I realize how difficult it is. So, congratulations to all of you.
You're very... you're very fortunate people. Alhamdu Lillah. I know you know it.
Okay, we'll just take the book from the cover.
A woman: I have a question.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, we planned it this way for a long time. No. That's another good sign, you know, cause
Here, well, the first time we got hold of the new Quran,
we were starting from the beginning of the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: ISBN.
A woman: ISBN.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. I see. Wow.
Did you tell me this before?
No, you already forgot it, but this is really something.
Yeah.
The ISBN number, this stands for International
Standard Book Number.
And it is a unique number that no other book in the world has it.
So, I guess if you add 934894 plus 57 plus 1, you get a divisible number. We didn't plan it. We didn't design it this way.
Okay.